Guide to the Yale School of Music Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale School of Music records of the dean
1915-2006
RU 460
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
98.75
(101 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, announcements, subject files, admissions data, grades, tuition records, and budgets documenting the faculty, students, and administration of the Yale School of Music, the Collection of Musical Instruments, and the Yale Summer School of Music and Art (Norfolk).
Yale School of Music
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 28-A (YRG 28-A), Central records and records of the dean of the Yale School of Music.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Biographical / Historical
In 1854, Joseph Battell donated money to Yale for the purpose of supporting instruction in music. The Yale Corporation approved the appointment of Gustave Jacob Stoeckel as an instructor in church music and other musical activities at Yale College in April of 1855. The Department of Music was established in 1889 and by 1890 Yale was offering its first credited courses in music. In 1894 Yale awarded its first Bachelor of Music degrees to a graduating class of four students. The graduate division was first established in 1932 and the Master of Music was first conferred in that year. In 1957 the Yale Corporation voted to change the status of the school to that of a graduate-professional school, and awarded the last Bachelor of Music degree in 1960. In 1968 Yale introduced a Master of Music and a Doctor of Music. Sprague Memorial Hall, completed in 1917 through a gift from the Sprague family, is part of the School of Music. Woolsey Hall, with a seating capavcity of 2,695, is the largest auditorium available to the school and houses the Newberry Memorial Organ. The Yale School of Music also includes the Institute of Sacred Music, as well as the Electronic Music Studio, the first studio of its kind in the country. The school is also affiliated with the Yale University Collection of Musical Instruments.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, announcements, subject files, admissions data, grades, tuition records, and budgets documenting the faculty, students, and administration of the Yale School of Music, the Collection of Musical Instruments, and the Yale Summer School of Music and Art (Norfolk).
Conservatories of music; Music -- Instruction and study; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale School of Music; Yale University. Summer School of Music and Art; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Collection of Musical Instruments; Norfolk Chamber Music Festival/Yale Summer School of Music
- Records, 1915-1970; Accession 1970-A-002
  - Admissions Data, 1946-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports [Department of Music], 1941-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports David Stanley Smith-Dean, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports Richard Donwan-Acting Dean, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports Bruce Simonds-Dean, 1942-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annaul Reports Bruce Simonds-Dean, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Assistants in Instruction [miscellaneous], 1955-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Audio-visual correspondence, 1955-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Baumgartner Recommendation for Curriculum Revision, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brazilian Artists' Visit [Operation Campus], 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budget [Department of Music]
    - 1939-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Budgets, 1920-1943 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Budget [miscellany], 1925-1943 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Budgets, 1939-1954 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Business Management [Service Bureaus] Correspondence, requisitions, etc. [See also: Box 11 Folder 135], 1946-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Centennial Celebration, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Chicago Arts Festival, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Collection of Musical Instruments correspondence miscellaneous, 1941-1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Collection of Musical Instruments reports and memos [Marcuse, Fuller, and Gushee], 1952-1961 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Collection of Musical Instruments Curator: R. Conant, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - College Music Association meeting at Yale, 1957 December 27-28 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Colloquium on Museums, Music, and Old Instruments at Yale, 1965 September 26 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Course of Study revisions, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Concert Artists contracts and correspondence, 1924-1938 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Concerts: Ensemble, Chamber, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Concerts
    - 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Concerts [Lectures, etc. correspondence], 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Concerts and Lectures, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Concerts and Lectures, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Concerts, Lectures, etc., 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Concerts, Lectures, etc., 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Concerts and Lectures, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Concerts, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Concerts, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Cooperative Research Project H-221 correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Cooperative Research Project H-221 Fiscal Data, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Cooperative Research Project H-221 Institute Data [Dean's Report], 1967 June - July (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Department of Music Graduate Division
    - 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Department of Music Undergraduate Division
    - 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Ditson Foreign Fellowship, 1933-1963 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Friends of Music at Yale, 1941-1948 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Friends of Music at Yale, 1950-1964 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - General Correspondence
    - 1915-1919 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - A - B, 1954-1970 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - C - F, 1954-1970 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - G - J, 1954-1970 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - K - L, 1954-1970 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - M, 1954-1970 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - N - R, 1954-1970 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - S, 1954-1970 (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - T - Z, 1954-1970 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Gifts, 1935-1940, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Harpsichords, 1944-1953 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Hess, Myra Carnegie Hall Recital [1952 Jan 27], 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Housing, Student, 1946-1955 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Library, General, 1941-1960 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Library - Gifts, 1938-1959 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Litchfield County Choral Union, 1948-1957 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Memos, Reports, Announcements to faculty, 1954-1968 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Music Education Appointment candidates, 1958-1959 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Music Education Program, 1958-1960 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - National Association of Schools of Music, 1927-1960 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Neighborhood Music School, 1943-1968 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - New Haven Symphony Orchestra; General, 1941-1958 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - New Haven Symphony Orchestra correspondence [Smith, Donovan, Simonds], 1925-1953 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Norfolk: Budget, etc.[Director's Report], 1960 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Norfolk: Programs and assorted memorabilia, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Norfolk: Staff
    - 1960 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - 1961 (Box 9, Folder 111)
    - 1962 (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - 1963 (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - 1964 (Box 9, Folder 114)
    - 1965 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - 1966 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - 1967 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Opera at Yale, 1942-1953 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Organ, Battell Chapel [construction of new Holtkamp organ], 1946, 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Organs: Divinity School, Dwight Chapel, Practice Instruments, 1953-1960 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Organs: Woolsey Hall (Newberry Memorial), 1953-1965 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Parker Centenneial, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Ph. D. in Theory at Yale, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Pianos-purchase and maintenance, 1923-1965 (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Pianos-maintenance [Loomis], 1958-1964 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Presidents Office correspondence with Dean Simonds, 1941-1953 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Provost-correspondence with School of Music Dean, 1934-1959 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Revision, 1958 "complete file of pertinent documents", 1955-1959 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Revision, 1958 correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Revision, 1958 Dean Noss' account of visits to other schools, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Revision, 1958 Dean Noss' worksheets, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Revision, 1958 Executive Officers' file [H. L. Smith], 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Secretary's Office correspondence with School of Music Dean, 1944-1955 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Service Bureau [See also Box 2 Folder 28], 1945-1955 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Sprague Hall: Building and Maintenance, 1917-1954 (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - Sprague Hall: requests for use of, 1959-1965 (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - Statistics and General Information, 1942-1953 (Box 12, Folder 139 - 140)
  - Stemann, Otto: Piano Tuning, 1944-1947 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - Stoeckel Hall Renovation, 1954-1955 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Student Council [minutes, etc.], 1946-1962 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Symposium Federation of Music Students, 1948-1952 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - Symposium of Contemporary Music International Federation of Music Students, Julliard Chapter, 1952 March 23-29 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Treasurer, 1942-1954 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - University Council Music Committee [Douglas Moore Chrmn.], 1948-1952 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - University Council Music Committee [Edw. Wardwell Chrmn.], 1952 April - 1953 December (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - University Council Music Committee [Edw. Wardwell Chrmn.], 1954 January - 1958 May (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - University Council Music Committee [R. Kimball Chrmn.], 1958 October - 1961 February (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Vassar merger plans in regard to music, 1962, 66-1967 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Woolsey Hall Concert Series Statements [Daggett Lee], 1940-1967 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Yale College Orchestra, 1939-1943 (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - Yale Seminar on Music Education, 1963-1965 (Box 13, Folder 155)
- Records of Bruce Simonds, 1932-1954; Accession 1974-A-003
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - A - Al, 1942-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Am - Az, 1942-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - B - Bl, 1942-1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bm - Bz, 1942-1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Band, Yale University, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Broadcasts, WYBC, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget, Department of Music, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - C - Cl, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cm - Cz, 1946-1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Corporation: Graduate Record Exam, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Catalogue, Department of Music, 1943-1944, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chamber Music Series
    - 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Concerts and Lectures, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - D - Dl, 1932, 1943-1946 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dm - Dz, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - E, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ensemble: Music Recitals, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ensemble concerts, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ensemble Concerts: Correspondence for Chamber Series, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Ensemble Series, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ensemble Series: Correspondence, 1932-1941 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ensemble Series: Financial, 1932-1941 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Equipment and Supplies, 1940, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - F, 1942-1952 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - G - Gl, 1945-1954 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Gm - Gz, 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Graduate School: Teaching Appointments, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - H - Hl, 1940-1952 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Hm - Hz, 1920, 1941-1952 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - I, 1942-1951 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - J, 1941-1949 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - K, 1941-1950 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - L, 1941-1950 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - M - MI, 1940-1950 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Mm - Mz, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Music Notation (Experimental), 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Music Rental Library, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Music Teacher's National Association, 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - N, 1942-1954 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - NYA Aid, 1941-1943 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - O, 1941, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - P - PI, 1940-1950 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Pm - Pz, 1940-1950 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Phonograph Records, 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Public School Music, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Questionnaires, 1945-1950 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - R, 1941-1950 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Regulations: Student Council, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - S - Sh, 1941-1951 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Sh - Ss, 1941-1951 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - St - Sz, 1941-1951 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Selective Service, 1944-1952 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Students: Questionnaires in Three Year Curriculum, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - T, 1941-1951 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - U, 1941-1951 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - V, 1941-1951 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - W - Wl, 1940-1952 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Wm - Wz, 1940-1952 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - WYBC Festival, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Woolsey Hall Series, 1950-1954 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Yale Budget Drive, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Yale University War Council: C. R. Walker, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - York Hall, 1938, 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 71)
- Records of the dean, 1956-1982; Accession 1984-A-019
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2058
  - Alumni Association, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Constitution, Proposed changes in, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Copies of 'Materials (schedules, address lists, etc.), 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Convocation
    - Materials, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Materials, 1973 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Materials, 1974 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Tapes, 1974 October (Box 1, Folder 7 - 8)
  - Alumni Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 10)
  - Alumni Day, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - At Norfolk, 1973 July 8 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alumni Fund
    - Business, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Class Agents, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Class-College List, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Information Materials, 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Letters and news received; copies of contribution receipts, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Letters In, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Letters Out, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Over $50 Letters, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Pink Sheets, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Receipts, Final, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Response, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Statistics - Working Notes, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Working File, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Working Notes (T. Fay), 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Working Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Alumi Mailing, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Alumni Meeting, NYC, 1973 February 28 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Alumni Meeting, Boston, 1973 May 6 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Alumni Newsletter, 1964 Nov, 1965 April (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Alumni Newsletter, Notes for, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Alumni Newsletter, Story Ideas for, 1967 February (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Board 'Members, 1959-1972 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Certificates of Merit (Proofs), 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 35 - 36)
  - Citations, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Glassboro State College -Department of Music ProgramsandCalendar of Events, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Letters, News, etc. received, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Mininberg, Ian - File on Matters during his Presidency, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Music Alumni, Old Files, Room BI, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - New York Student-Alumni Meeting, 1974 March 8 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Norfolk List, Additions to #1, #5, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 45 - 46)
  - Opera - Lyric Opera of Chicago, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Seminars, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 48 - 49)
  - Yale Daily News, 1974 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Yale Graduate Professional, 1978 February 13 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Yale Philharmonia of Kennedy Center (Box 4)
    - Alumni Mailings, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Announcements, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Proofs, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Yale School of Music Newsletter, 1956-1964 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - RESTRICTED
    - Applications
      - LaCivita, Marilynn, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Faculty
  - Personnel
- Records, circa 1959-1980; Accession 1989-A-119
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2015
  - Council on Planning and Priorities Charles H. Foster, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Director: Yale Symphony - Applicants, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Band Directors, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Band Director Search, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Buckeley Amendment: Policies, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Civic Center - Spencer M. Berger, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Prospective Faculty, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Prospective Faculty, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bliss, Anthony: Metropolitan Opera, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Borowski, Karol: Committee on Cultural Relations with Poland, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brewster, Kingman Jr., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Curtis, Mark - President: Scripps College, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - De Butts, John D. - Chairman: ATandT, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Graffman, Gary, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Luce, Henry Mr. and Mrs., 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Records, circa 1930-1983; Accession 1989-A-121
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018
  - MMA auditions [see Box 24], 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 79-1980 Admissions [see Box 24], 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Admissions: YSM and Norfolk [see Box 24], 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Admissions Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Auditions-1977, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Admissions 1976-1977 [see Box 24], 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - National Auditions '74 and Admissions Information [see Box 24], 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alumni Convocation - 10/15, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Reunion - 4/29-30, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alumni Executive Committee - 8/30, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Convocation - 10/15-16, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alumni Convocation - 10/11, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Afumni Convocation, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Convocation - 10/10-11, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Alumni Association 50th Reunion - 5/23, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alumni Convocation, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Afumni Day at Norfolk, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Alumni Day at Norfolk - 6/28, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alumni Meeting -- New York City: Yale Club - Feb., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alumni Meeting -- New York City: Yale Club - 3/8/74, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Career Placement, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Alumni Board, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Association of Yale Alumni Assembly XIV April 5-197, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Association of Yale Alumni Assembly, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Association of Yale Alumni Assembly, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Convocation: 10/14-16, for Association of Yale Alumni/Campaign for Yale, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Association of Yale Alumni Meeting - April 11, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence and Gifts, 1960-1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Commencement
    - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1977 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - General Information for YSM Commencement, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bicentennial, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Comittee of Fourteen, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Notes for Committee of Fourteen, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Executive Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - University Council: Music Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - University Council: Music Committee - R. Philip Hanes, Jr., Chairman, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Faculty Steering Committee [see Box 24], 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Performance Committee, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Performance Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - University Council Committee on Music, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - University Council Meeting, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Performance Committee Requests [see Box 24], 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Performance Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Permanent Officers Committee [see Box 24], 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Music at Yale - 6/74, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Applications for Concert Coordinator [see Box 24], 1969 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Concert Office, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Saito/Toho Orchestra - Oct., 1974 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Danny Kaye Benefit Concert, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - FM Radio Station, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Ives Recording, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Mahagonny Recording, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Symphony News, 1963-1973 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Concert Requests, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Concert Series, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - General Music Events, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Piccini Opera - Joe Clark, Bill Harwood, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - National Opera Institute, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Contracts: Reference, etc. (Organs), 1964-1971 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Organs: Kisrgbaum, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Philip F. Nelson [General Correspondence]
    - 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Monday Convocations, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Schedules, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Curriculum Program and Related Material, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Curriculum, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Curriculum, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Curriculum, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Courses, Schedules, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Ellington, undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - National Endowment for the Arts: Music Policy Conference, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Ives Centennial, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Ives Centennial, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Vienna - General, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Vienna Legalities, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Vienna Expenses, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Vienna News Releases, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 89)